# Toni Lozano Fernández

Barcelona, Spain | aj.lozano.fernandez@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | +34 686667152

#### Resume

I am a self-driven iOS Developer, life learner with professional background in electronic industry. After more than 10 years in electronic engineering I've acquired a solid base in problem solving and low level programming. In that stage I developed projects that required hardware design and firmware development to implement embedded systems, which allowed me to understand the importance of efficient code, attention to detail, good communication and great teamwork skills.

In recent years the mobile sector has awakened my interest, specifically the iOS technology, which has given me to develop several projects and create my own apps. However, my adventure in the mobile sector began with the development of small projects in Android.

I also feel great passion for gamedev, where I've been able to create basic projects with Unreal Engine and something more complex in Unity.

### **Skills & Technologies**

### iOS development:

Swift | Xcode | Firebase | UIKit | SwiftUI | Networking | JSON parsing | Core Data | Realm | Core Location | Auto Layout | MVC & MVVM | VIPER | Cocoapods | TDD | Git | Github | Object-oriented programming | Clean code

#### Game development:

Unity | C# | C++ | Visual Studio | 3D | 2D | OOP | Clean code | Git | Github

### Android development:

Android SDK | Java | Kotlin | Xml | MVC & MVVM | RESTful APIs | SQLite | Firebase | OOP | Git | Github

#### Others:

Microsoft Project | Agile methodologies | Slack | Trello | Notion | Source Tree

### Experience

#### 2022-Now Freelance

Position: Freelance developer

Tasks: Develop own projects for iOS devices using Swift. Identify and troubleshoot technical issues

in applications, as well as perform thorough testing and debugging to ensure solid, bug-free

performance.

Since the mobile development field is rapidly evolving, I must keep up to date on the latest trends, technologies and best practices. In addition to researching and learning new tools, frameworks and APIs relevant to the iOS platform, all while keeping in mind to maintain clean

and efficient code by using SOLID principles.

## iOS Developer

2016-2022 Neec Audio Barcelona

Position: Hardware designer

Tasks: Responsible of hardware design oriented to Professional Audio devices whith innovative

solutions.

2014-2016 Zolertia S.L.

Position: Hardware and Firmware developer

Tasks: Responsible of all Hardware design and firmware development for products like Z1,

Re-mote, etc. Including schematics design and PCB multi-layer, component selection and

verification based on circuit simulation, prototype testing.

**2008-2014** Advancare S.L. Position: R+D Technician

Tasks: Project development in all stages of production of custom-made devices, from planning to

spec documentation, hardware design, firmware development, integration and testing.

### Academic training

2022-2022 Universitat Oberta de Catalunya

Android development course.

2018-2019 UNIR - La universidad de internet

Game design and development master degree

2018-2018 Institut Obert de Catalunya

CFGS Multiplatform Application development

2006-2008 Institut Escola del Treball

CFGS Electronic products development

### **Certifications & other courses**

2022 iOS & Swift - The Complete iOS App Development Bootcamp

Udemy - Angela Yu

2022 Beginning C++ Programming - From Beginner to Beyond

Udemy - Dr. Frank Mitropoulos

2015 An Introduction to Interactive Programming in Python (Part 1) (Part 2)

Coursera

### Other

Languages English: C1

Spanish: Native Catalan: Native